So now that we learn the absolute trick and
虽然我们学习了绝对值技巧
the square trick and how they are used in linear regression,
和平方技巧 以及如何在线性回归中使用
we still want to have some intuition on how these things get figured out.
我们还希望了解这些如何计算出来的
These tricks still seem a little too magical,
这些技巧看似非常神秘
and we'd like to find their origin.
所以我们希望寻根溯源
So let's do this in a much more formal way.
那么我们要以更加正式的方式进行
Let's say we have our points,
例如我们有几个点
and our plan is to develop an algorithm which will
想要开发个算法
find the line that best fits this set of points.
能够找到拟合这些点的直线
And the algorithm works like this.
这个算法具体如下
First, it will draw a random line and it'll calculate the error.
首先绘制一条随机直线 可以计算误差
The error is some measure of how far the points are from the line.
这个误差为点到直线的距离值
In this drawing, it looks like it's the sum of these distances,
在这个图中 误差为这些距离的总和
but it could be any measure that tells us how far we are from the points.
但是它也可以是一种测度 告诉我们离这些点有多远
Now we're going to move the line around and see if we can decrease this error.
我们将要移动这个直线 观察一下是否可以降低误差
We move in this direction and we see that the error kind of increases,
我们向这个方向移动 看到误差增加
so that's not the way to go.
所以不应该这样移动
So we move in the other direction and see that the error decreased,
我们向另一个方向移动 看到误差减少
so we picked this one and stay there.
所以应该使用这个 并保持不动
Now we'll repeat the process many times over and over,
现在我们不断重复这个过程
every time descending the error a bit,
每次都将误差减少一点
until we get to the perfect line.
直到得到最合适的直线
So to minimize this error,
为了减少误差
we're going to use something called a gradient descent.
我们将使用梯度下降法
So let me talk a bit about gradient descent.
所以我们来了解一下梯度下降法
The way it works is we're standing here on top of a mountain, this is called Mt.
这种方法相当于我们站在山顶 这叫做误差山 (Mount Rainierror)
Rainierror, as it measures how big our error is.
可以测算误差的大小
And we want to descend from this mountain.
我们想从山顶下来
In order to descend from this mountain,
为了从山顶下来
we need to minimize our height.
我们需要将高度减少至最小
And on the left we have a problem of fitting the line to the data,
在左边 我们面临直线拟合数据的问题
which we can do by minimizing the error or the distance from the line to the points.
通过缩小误差 或者缩小点到直线的距离
So descending from the mountain is equivalent to getting the line closer to the points.
所以下山相当于让直线更靠近这些点
Now if you want to descend from the mountain,
现在如果你想下山
we would look at the directions where we can walk down
我们要观察往哪个方向走
and find the one that makes us descend the most.
然后找到让我们下降幅度最大的方向
And let's say this is direction.
例如这个方向
So we descend a bit in this direction.
所以我们沿着这个方向下山
This is equivalent to getting the line a little bit closer to the points.
这相当于让直线一点点逼近这些点
So in our height is smaller because we're closer to
我们的高度越小 因为我们越靠近
the points since our distance to them is smaller.
这些点 到这些点的距离就越小
And again and again, we look at what makes his descent the most from the mountain,
不断重复 我们观察如何让它下降幅度最大
and let's say we get here.
可以说我们到这儿
Now we're at a point where we've descended from the mountain,
现在我们到达下山的地点
and on the right, we found the line that is very close to our points.
在右边 我们看到直线距离这些点非常接近
Thus, we've solved our problem,
这样我们解决了问题
and that is gradient descent.
这就是梯度下降法
In a more mathematical way,
从数学角度来说
what happens to the following.
具体过程如下
We have a plot, and here's a plot in two dimensions.
我们有个绘图 这个图有两个维度
Although in reality, the plot will be in higher dimensions.
虽然在实际过程中 绘图可能会包含多个维度
We have our weights on the x-axis,
权重位于 x 轴
and our error on the y-axis.
误差位于 y 轴
And we have an error function that looks like this.
并且还有一个这样的误差函数
We're standing over here and the way to descend is to actually take
我们站在此处 下降方法实际上
the derivative or gradient of the error function with respect to the weights.
针对权重的导数或误差梯度函数
This gradient is going to point to a direction where the function increases the most.
梯度指出了函数增加至最大时的方向
Therefore, the negative of this gradient is going to point
所以梯度为负值 表明
down in the direction where the function decreases the most.
方向朝下时 函数减少到最小
So what we do is, we take a step in the direction of the negative of that gradient.
所以我们要向梯度负值方向迈出一步
This means, we're taking our weight, W_i,
这表明我们对权值 W i
and changing them to W_i minus the derivative of the error with respect to W_i.
改为 W i 减去 W i 的误差导数
In real life, we'll be multiplying this derivative by
在实际生活中 我们会用这个导数
the learning rate since we want to make small steps.
乘以学习率 因为我们只想迈出一小步
This means, the error function is decreasing,
这表明误差函数正在下降
and we're closer to the minimum.
并且我们更加接近最小值
If we do this several times,
如果反复进行几次
we get to either a minimum or pretty good value where the error is small.
我们将会得到最小值 或者误差极小的较优值
Once we get to that point,
我们一旦到达这个点
then we've reached a pretty good solution for our linear regression problem.
就能得到线性回归问题的较优解
And that's what gradient descent is all about.
这就是梯度下降法的内容